The Dunbar Library & Archive is one of the products
of the Dunbar Initiative at the University of Dayton.
The public website is the result of a cohort of students and scholars
who have gathered and generated collections of resources from all over the world.
The DLA contributors and curators interact with images, places, manuscripts, and performances
from the life and times of the Dunbar Family and encode them as Linked Open Data.
Each record included in the DLA has been discovered, described, and enhanced
before a project curator has released it.
Some collections are already well organized and described, requiring few annotations.
Others may cherry pick records from, for example, a national collection of black authors,
or add discerning details to generically described library records.
Our correspondence collection is largely comprised of digital images from the University of
Delaware library.
However, a team of undergraduate students has been adding information and transcriptions.
These new annotations draw the UDel records into the DLA and grant them superpowers.
By non-destructively enhancing each record, scholars gain easier discovery,
records can be related to each other and classified, and new documents can be generated
to visualize this intimate record of an American life and relationship in meaningful ways.
Users may want to interact with a transcription interface at https://t-pen.org,
Each transcription is a resource itselfavailable to a wide variety of tools for inspection
and study.
It is now possible to inspect the handwriting, cataloger's notes, or material features.
And it is possible to focus on the text, identifying themes, orthography, and structure.
These projects may be used by future scholars to describe the people and places recorded
in the letters, or to provide contextual links or essays to the events or concepts mentioned.
In addition to the accessibility through the Linked Open Data graph, these new contributions to
Dunbar scholarship are all available in the first of its kind virtual library and archive where
scattered collections and new scholarship integrate with a focus on the life of
Paul Laurence Dunbar and his impact on our communities, literature, and world.
The letters we've been describing are collected and searchable.
Each entry retains its connections, so a student may discover the transcription project,
the library record at the University of Delware, or explore relationships to other DLA entries.
Different collections may have different connections to explore.
The Complete Poems are encoded in the DLA and annotated with invaluable resources.
"A Banjo Song" is a dialect poem that includes a spoken performance to aid understanding.
A linked glossary from University of Dayton provides granualar help with challenging terms.
These helpful resources are linked, of course, and have merely been discovered at the DLA.
Some poems have musical settings, available in a linked database of composers.
The DLA record brings together several manifestations of the poetry, providing
a useful summary and many paths forward.
This poem has links out to musical settings, a poem entry at University of Dayton eCommons,
and the TEI-XML encoding of The Complete Poems.
The DLA will continue to grow. Existing entries will be enhanced with new scholarship and
connections. Project curators are reviewing and accessioning new collections all the time.
The DLA is a place for students to explore, scholars to research, and the public to
discover the significance of Paul Dunbar.